<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>how-to on Qoherent Technical Blog</title>
    <link>http://qoherent.net/categories/how-to/</link>
    <description>Recent content in how-to on Qoherent Technical Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 01:16:34 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://qoherent.net/categories/how-to/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Run GNU Radio in a Python Virtual Environment.</title>
      <link>http://qoherent.net/blog/gnu_radio_python_virtual_environment_venv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 01:16:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://qoherent.net/blog/gnu_radio_python_virtual_environment_venv/</guid>
      <description>Pull an External GNU Radio Installation into your Python Virtual Environment This article explains how to access your system-level GNU Radio installation from within a pre-existing Python virtual environment. After completing these steps, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to import GNU Radio or any of its subpackages into your Python modules using simple import statements, such as: from gnuradio import gr.
We provide an explanation and a recommendation before the solution, but to jump straight to the solution, click here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to connect to the screen of an android phone remotely with SCRCPY and SSH.</title>
      <link>http://qoherent.net/blog/scrcpy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 01:16:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://qoherent.net/blog/scrcpy/</guid>
      <description>How to install Scrcpy to mirror Android phone Scrcpy, referred to as “Screen Copy” is an open-source software enabling a PC to remote control an Android phone that is either connected through USB or through WIFI.
Scrcpy is a great way to remotely control an UE as part of a 5G or OpenRAN development activity. Qoherent uses Scrcpy to control our UE’s remotely, as part of collaborations with partner companies in other cities, and to enable our team to work remotely and independently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting an Analog Devices ADALM-PLUTO working on ubuntu server.</title>
      <link>http://qoherent.net/blog/pluto_ubuntu_server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 01:16:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://qoherent.net/blog/pluto_ubuntu_server/</guid>
      <description>The ADI ADALM Pluto is a great device for prototyping SDR solutions. It is compatible with [GNU Radio(https://wiki.gnuradio.org/index.php/PlutoSDR_Source)], has a python API, and is a great utility that is readily commercially available. It is even the subject of a widely availible course on DSP, pySDR.
At Qoherent, we use it for all sorts of applications with all kinds of workstations. One common use case is with our portable ubuntu server systems.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
